Guide to the Guido H. Marx Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Guido H. Marx papers
1893-1949
SC0129
Marx, Guido H., (Guido Hugo), 1871-1949.
7.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Barbara Marx Givan, 1966, 1986, and 1990.
Information about Access
None.
Bibliography
Folder 1: The process of invention. Stanford Univ. Engineering Journal, May, 1897, pp. 69-71.
What should college professors be paid? Atlantic Monthly, v. 95, May, 1905, pp. 647-50.
Condition and needs of the Univ. of Calif. Discussion. Trans. Commonwealth Club, 1907.
Value of drawing in practical life. Calif. Teachers' Quarterly, June, 1907, pp. 77-84.
Notes on machine drawing. Stanford University. 15p. 1905, 1907,
The making of the Stanford Engineer. Stanford Alumnus, Dec. 1907, p. 127-32.
Isometric plotting of graphical charts. Am. Mach., v. 31, Nov. 12, 1903, pp. 7-13
Report of committee of Cornell Club of Northern Calif. on improvement of salaries (with J.M. Chase and R.B. Daggett). Cornell Alumni News, May 6, 1908.
Folder 2: Some trends in higher education. Science, May 14, 1909, p. 759-97.
Reform in San Francisco. Nation, July 1, 1909.
Some trends in higher education. Science, July 16, 1909, p. 87-89.
The college forum. The American College, v. 1, no. 1, October 1909, pp. 56-68.
Folder 3: The problem of the assistant professor. Journal Assoc. of American Universities, 1910, pp. 17-47; and Science, 1910: pp. 401-406, 441-450, and 488-497.
Some trends in higher education. Calif. Weekly, June 10, 1910, p. 459-60.
Attendance of students at foreign universities. Science, v. 31, April 29, 1910.
University fellowships. Science, v. 33, March 31, 1911, pp. 491-92.
Folder 4: Should the same salary be paid to men bearing the same titles? Bryn Mawr Alumnae Quarterly, v. 5, p. 1-4, April, 1911.
Committee of Ten. Minority Report to the Academic Council. 18p. 1911. [Stanford University].
Strength of gear teeth. Trans. A.S.M.E., v. 34, p. 1323-98, 1912.
Strength of gear teeth. 2nd. paper. Trans. A.S.M.E., v. 37, p.503-30, 1915.
An engineer's acid test of patriotism. The Standard, v. 6, May, 1920.
Some comparative wear experiments on cast iron gear teeth (with L.E. Cutter and B.M Green). Mech. Engineering, v. 48, p. 33-36, Jan., 1926.
How to control public utilities. Nation, v. 132, no. 3430, April 1, pp. 348-50.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Guido H. Marx was born in Toledo, Ohio, in 1871. He attended Cornell University, earning the degree of mechanical engineer in 1893. He worked in industry for two years before joining the Stanford faculty in 1895, at the instigation of Albert W. Smith, his former professor at Cornell who, in collaboration with Guido's brother Charles D. Marx, was developing Stanford's new School of Engineering. He became professor of machine design in 1908; he retired in 1936 with the rank of Professor Emeritus.
In addition to authoring a treatise on Machine Design with Prof. Smith, his professional activities included research in the fields of gearing and bearing lubrication, advocating vocational guidance for Stanford students, co-founding the American Association of University Professors, and holding office in the American Federation of Teachers.
Prof. Marx was also actively involved in many political and social issues. In Palo Alto, he served on the planning commission and the School Board and played an instrumental role in the construction of its first municipal power plant. In 1911 he and Professor R.L. Green organized the local branch of the Progressive Party; Marx was the official delegate to its 1912 national convention. He was active in the American Civil Liberties Union, especially around issues of labor organization and repeal of the Criminal Syndicalism Law.
In 1895 Guido H. Marx married Gertrude Van Dusen, a member of the Cornell library staff; they had four children. He died in 1949.
Scope and Contents note
Additional papers were received in 1986 and 1990; they have been added to the collection as two addenda rather than interfiled with the previously processed papers. Each addition has been identified by its accession number (86-179 and 90-188) and is listed separately. When requesting materials from these additions, please indicate the accession number on the paging slip.
An index to selected correspondents in the entire collection is included in this guide, along with a listing of Guido Marx's articles and reprints in Box 3.
SCOPE NOTE
The papers of Guido H. Marx include correspondence, speeches, a typed autobiography, reprints, press releases, clippings, minutes, reports, and pamphlets, 1898-1949, and Marx's thesis from Cornell, A Study of Special Tools and Methods Used in the Manufacture of Small Engines, 1893.
The papers document both his academic career at Stanford and his political interests. His academic life is represented by correspondence with faculty, 1898-1905; reprints of his engineering and educational articles; and minutes, reports, and other records from his departmental duties in the School of Engineering. His political life is represented by correspondence, speeches, articles, and pamphlets pertaining to efforts to repeal criminal syndicalism laws, labor and unionization efforts, the Sacco-Vanzetti case, cooperatives, and control of public utilities. Organizations appearing in his papers include the American Association of University Professors, the American Civil Liberties Union, the American Federation of Teachers, the Pacific Co-operative League, Inc., the National Popular Government League, the California State Water and Power League, and the People's Legislative Service.
Arrangement note
The first ten boxes of the collection consist of the original papers that were received and arranged in 1966. Only the letters in Box 1 were given full treatment, with incoming and outgoing letters arranged together chronologically. Other sections were arranged or left as received, depending upon the accessibility of the original arrangement. In some cases, letters pertinent to the subject were left in the appropriate folders rather than being integrated into the chronological arrangement.
Access Terms
American Association of University Professors..; American Civil Liberties Union.; American Federation of Teachers..; Baldwin, Roger N., (Roger Nash), 1884-1981.; Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977; Cooke, Morris Llewellyn,, 1872-1960.; Coolidge, Mary Roberts,, 1860-1945.; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965.; Hayes, E. A., (Everis Anson), 1855-1942.; Hichborn, Franklin,, 1869-1963.; Hill, Albert Ross.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Jourdin, Willis W.; Lewis, Austin,, 1865?-1944.; Monroe, Paul,, 1869-1947.; National Popular Government League..; Norris, George W., (George William), 1861-1944.; Pacific Co-operative League, Inc..; People's Legislative Service..; Rolfe, Henry W.; Rowell, Chester H.; Sinclair, Upton,, 1878-1968.; Stanford University. School of Engineering. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Veblen, Thorstein,, 1857-1929.; Whitney, Anita,, 1867-1955.; Cooperative societies.; Criminal syndicalism.; Engineering--Study and teaching.; Public utilities--Law and legislation.; Public utilities.; Sacco-Vanzetti Trial, Dedham, Mass., 1921.
Collection Contents
- Original Papers, 1897-1949
  - Correspondence, 1901-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from other Stanford faculty, 1898-1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters to his wife, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters between Joseph Dorfman and Marx, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Criminal syndicalism correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal letters on retiring, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Speeches: (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - (1) Scientific management, (1913 or 1914)
    - (2) A study of intelligence testing, with historical comment by Marx, 1926
  - Speeches: (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - (3) The rational of public utility ownership, (1930)
    - (4) War and the Conscientious Objector, (1936)
    - (5) Education at times of crisis, (1936)
    - (6) Engineering and social function (at New School)
    - (7) The Engineer and the Social Sciences, undated
  - Speeches: (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - (8) Economic aspects of the ownership of public utilities, (1938)
    - (9) The Scientific spirit in University Organization, (1914)
    - (10) Production-- what ails it?, (1920)
    - (11) Retrospect, 1924
  - Speeches: (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - (12) Some phases of motor automation, (1916)
    - (13) What do you propose to do about it?, (1906)
    - (14) The aim of engineering education, (1911)
    - (15) Untitled. Concerned with definition of an engineer and his values. Possibly Stanford Alumni Conference of 1935 (q.v.) Power--From the Engineer's Viewpoint
    - (16) Untitled
    - (17) A critical examination of certain objections to the affiliation of teachers with the American Federation of Teachers
    - (18) Lecture to P.T.A. concerning California Federation of Teachers.
  - 1931 trip to Russia, includes short autobiography of experience. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Biographical material, 1901-1905 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Biographical material, 1908-1920 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Biographical material, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Biographical material, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Biographical material, 1924-1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Biographical material, 1929-37 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Autobiography: Why so Hot, Little Man? (my scrapbook). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Autobiography. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Autobiography--Stanford University. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Autobiography. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Autobiography: Talks--Part I. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Autobiography: Talks--Part II. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Autobiography: Salary Investigation. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Autobiography: Expulsion Case. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Autobiography: Appendix A. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Autobiography: Appendix B. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Autobiography: Appendix C. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Autobiography: Miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1897-1908 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1911-1931 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Report on depth-pressure records for oil wells. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lecture: Man's Cooperation with Nature. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lecture: Power--a political issue from an engineer's viewpoint. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - American Federation of Teachers-- California Section. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American Federation of Teachers-- California Section. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Two books: Machine Design. (Box 3, Folder NF)
  - American Federation of Teachers-- California Section. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - American Federation of Teachers-- California Section. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - American Federation of Teachers-- California Section. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Teachers: articles, news releases. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - American Federation of Teachers: articles, news releases. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - American Federation of Teachers: articles, news releases. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Co-operative League, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Pacific Co-operative League, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Pacific Co-operative League, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pacific Co-operative League, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Peninsular Economic Exchange. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - New School for Social Research: notes, lectures. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - New School for Social Research. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - New School for Social Research. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New School for Social Research: Correspondence with Veblen. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sacco-Vanzetti Case. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Water and Power Act. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - California State Water and Power League. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hetch Hetchy. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Anon. Los Angeles fights the power trust. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Deposition of Francis J. Heney, Trial of Patrick. San Francisco graft trials., 10 Mar, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Murphy Name Plate Scandal. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Vocational guidence studies. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cornell salary report. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Intelligence tests. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Committees. Original sources. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - School of Engineering. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - School of Engineering: Curriculum Committee. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - School of Engineering: Curriculum Committee. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - School of Engineering: Curriculum Committee. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mechanical Engineering Department: Business. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mechanical Engineering 219--Seminar. Reading lists. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Mechanics applied to engineering. Exam. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Problems in machine design. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Citizenship Course, syllabus. Lecture: Man's Cooperation with Nature. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - University staff and salary data. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlet Collection (listed by organization or subject):
    - American Association for Economics. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - American Civil Liberties Union. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - American Committee of Justice. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - American Economic League. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - American Federation of Labor. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - American Peace Society, Advocate of Peace. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Associated Railway Employees Organization. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Barrados League. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - California Federation of Teachers. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - California State Federation of Labor. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Conscientious Objectors. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Co-operative Society of Weinstock, Lubin, and Company. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Education Protective Association of America. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Joseph Fels Fund of America. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Free Speech League. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Henry George, The Study of Political Economy. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Franklin Hichborn, public utilities. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Franklin Hichborn, articles and testimony of Eustace Cullinan before Senate Judiciary Committee. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Humanist Addresses (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - International Committee for Political Prisoners. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - I.W.W. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Japanese Association of America. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - League for Industrial Democracy. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Methodist Federation for Social Service. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Thomas Mooney (subject). (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - National Coal Association. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - National Conservation Association. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - New Crusade. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - National Popular Government League, 1923-26 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - National Popular Government League, 1927-28 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - National Popular Government League, 1929-30 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - National Popular Government League, 1931-33 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - National Popular Government League, 1934-45 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - National Popular Government League, 1946-49 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - National Popular Government League, Miscellaneous. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - National Popular Government League, pamphlets and clippings. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - National Progressive Campaign. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - National Progressive Convention. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - People's Legislative Service. (Ray Lyman Wilbur vs People's Legislative Service.) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - People's Legislative Service: The People's Business, 1923-27 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - People's Legislative Service: The People's Business, 1928-31 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Plumb Plan League. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Progressive Labor Party. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Progressive National Committee. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Public Ownership League of America. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Public Utilities. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Rand School of Social Service. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Single Tax. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Spreckles, Rudolph. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Technocracy. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Worker's Party of America. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - World Federation. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Additional Papers, 1905-1923; Accession ARCH-1986-179
  - Correspondence pertaining to and reviews of Machine Design, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence pertaining to earthquake relief, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Everis A. Hayes, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Franklin Hichborn, 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence relating to the Daily Palo Alto, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, American Association of University Professors, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with James Harvey Robinson, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General correspondence, 1905-1908 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General correspondence, January-June, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence, July-December 1909 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General correspondence, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General correspondence, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General correspondence, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General correspondence, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General correspondence, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers: reports, circulars, etc. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Stanford faculty matters: minutes, resolutions, and reports, 1906-1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Statement by G.H. Marx concerning case of Prof. H.W. Rolfe (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clippings about college faculty and promotions (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous items: statement on woman suffrage poem to Jane Addams, platform of the Santa Clara County Republican Convention, and others, 1911, 1912, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Stanford publications with annotations by G.H. Marx: Trustees Manual, Organization, General Legislation, and Standing Regulations of the Faculty, and Manual of Faculty Organization...and General Resolutions of the Board of Trustees, 1908; 1913; 1920 (Box 1, Folder nf)
  - Bulletin of the American Association of University Professors. Report of the committee of inquiry concerning charges of violation of academic freedom...at the University of Montana. Vol. III, No. 5, May 1917 (Box 1, Folder nf)
- Additional Papers, 1893-1936; Accession ARCH-1990-188
  - American Civil Liberties Union
    - Correspondence, 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, January-July, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, August-September, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, October-December, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, fragments, circa 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, January-May, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, June, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, July, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, August-November, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Criminal syndicalism law, correspondence, 1920-1923 and undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Criminal syndicalism law, correspondence, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Criminal syndicalism law, correspondence, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Criminal syndicalism law, miscellaneous leaflets, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Kinkead, Beatrice: letters from Anita Whitney, and Anna Porter, undated, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Organization of California ACLU: notes and outline by G.H. Marx, circa 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Marx, G.H.: quotations and miscellaneous notes (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Committee for Immediate Defense of Constitutional Rights, checkbook, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Charlotte Anita Whitney pardon: petitions, pamphlets, clippings, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Better America Federation: pamphlet on industrial reforms and response by Franklin Hichborn (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Pamphlets, ACLU (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Pamphlets, California Branch of the General Defense Committee (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Pamphlets, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Pamphlets, Sacco and Vanzetti (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Public Utilities
    - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Control of public utilities: papers, clippings, articles, and a letter from the Stanford Alumni Conference, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Control of public utilities: speech drafts (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Government ownership of power: clippings, articles, notes (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Power - From an Engineer's Viewpoint: typescript speech (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - LSJU Founding Grant: excerpts re cooperation (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Stanford University, School of Engineering
    - Reports, memoranda, correspondence concerning re-organization of the School, 1920-1926 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Mechanical Engineering Lab plan: blueprint and letter/report to C.D. Marx, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Marx, G.H., reprints of articles: The Problem of the Assistant Professor, and Some Trends in Higher Education, 1910, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Stanford photographs and miscellany, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Marx, Guido H., A Study of Special Tools and Methods Used in the Manufacture of Small Engines, a thesis presented at Cornell University for the degree of M.E., 1893 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Membership certificates for Society of Mechanical Engineers, and Sigma Xi, and diplomas from Toledo Public High School, and Cornell University, 1901, 1893; 1887, 1893 (Box 4 oversize)
Selected List of Correspondents
Addis, Thomas
Bailey, Forrest 90-188: Box 1, Folder 7-8, 10
Baldwin, Roger N. 90-188: Box 1, Folder 1, 3-5, 11
Benne, Adron A. Box 4, Folder 1-2
Bjornson, Anga M.
Black, Marshall 86-179: Box 1, Folder 2, 12
Bliven, Bruce 90-188: Box 3, Folder 1
Browne, Andrew A. Box 1, Folder 4
Cooke, Morris Llewellyn
Coolidge, Mary Roberts 90-188: Box 1, Folder 4-5
Copeland, Clement A. Box 1, Folder 4
Dart, Anna C.
Dorfman, Joseph Box 1, Folder 6
Durand, William F.
Farrand, Max Box 1, Folder 4
Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley 90-188: Box 1, Folder 3
Frankfurter, Felix 90-188: Box 3, Folder 1
Garrison, J. C. Box 3, Folder 9
Hayes, Everis A. 86-179: Box 1, Folder 3
Hichborn, Franklin
Hill, Albert Ross 86-179: Box 1, Folder 9, 11
Hoover, Herbert Box 1, Folder 3
Hoover, Theodore J. 90-188: Box 3, Folder 10
Johnson, Hiram Box 1, Folder 3
Johnston, Mercer G. 90-188: Box 3, Folder 2
Jones, Hubert C. 90-188: Box 1, Folder 7
Jordan, David Starr
Jourdin, Willis W.
Leidy, Emma Brown Box 1, Folder 8
Lewinsohn, Joseph L. 86-179: Box 1, Folder 15-16
Lewis, Austin 90-188: Box 1, Folder 9
Monroe, Paul
National Popular Govt. League Box 1, Folder 3
Norris, George W. Box 1, Folder 2
Porter, Anna Box 5, Folder 5
Roberts, Holland D. Box 3, Folder 8-9
Robinson, Elmo A. 90-188: Box 1, Folder 4-5, 7
Robinson, James Harvey 86-179: Box 1, Folder 7
Rolfe, Henry W. Box 1, Folder 4
Rowell, Chester H. 86-179: Box 1, Folder 11, 15
Saunders, Frederick A. 90-188: Box 3, Folder 10
Silliman, John C. Box 6, Folder 3
Slosson, Edwin E. 86-179: Box 1, Folder 9-10
Smith, Albert. W.
Solow, Herbert 90-188: Box 2, Folder 3
Stanley, Edward J. Box 1, Folder 4
Steinmetz, Harry C.
Veblen, Thorstein Box 5, Folder 4
Willoughby, Ray R. Box 6, Folder 3
Wilson, Woodrow W. 86-179: Box 1, Folder 9